Rodney H. True Papers 1846-1939 1913-1939 Mss.B.T763
American Philosophical Society
Rodney H. True Papers
1861-1939
Mss.B.T763
American Philosophical Society
6.0 Linear feet
The plant physiologist and historian Rodney H. True (1866-1940) divided his career relatively evenly between the Bureau of Plant Industry in United States Department of Agriculture and the Department of Botany and Morris Arboretum of the University of Pennsylvania. A specialist in the physiological function of mineral nutrients in plants, True was active in his later career in the Philadelphia Society for Promoting Agriculture, the Pennsylvania Horticulture Society, and the Agricultural History Society. The True Papers consist of 6 linear feet of material relating primarily to the period of his career spent at the University of Pennsylvania. The collection contains roughly equal proportions of personal and professional correspondence, with a few diaries and research notebooks documenting his involvement with professional organizations and his interests in the history of his discipline.
True, Rodney H.(Rodney Howard), 1866-1940
Box 1-12
Bibliography
Schafer, Joseph, "Rodney Howard True: A Wisconsin Gift to Washington and Philadelphia," Wisconsin Magazine of History 24, 3 (1941), 336-356.
Edwards, Everett E., "Rodney H. True and His Writings," Agricultural History 18 (1944), 23-34. Includes a complete bibliography for True.
Related Archival Materials note
The Papers of the Philadelphia Society for Promoting Agriculture are available in the Rare Books and Manuscripts Library at the University of Pennsylvania (Ms. Coll. 92).
True appears as a correspondent in the Papers of William Jacob Robbins (Ms. Coll. 92).
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Accessioned 1957.
Scope and Contents note
The True Papers consist of 6 linear feet of materials relating to the life and career of the plant physiologist, Rodney H. True. In addition to 4.5 linear feet of correspondence, divided approximately equally between personal and professional, the collection includes ten diaries, 29 notebooks, and a number of photographs and other miscellaneous items.
The picture that emerges of True is intriguing, but often all too sparse. Coming almost exclusively from the last twenty years of his career, the collection primarily reflects True's late-career interests. Initially a general botanist, and subsequently a plant physiologist, by the time True landed at the University of Pennsylvania in 1920, his research interests centered largely on the history of his discipline, with a particular focus on Thomas Jefferson, John and William Bartram, and the plant sciences in early Philadelphia. As a result, his important work at the U.S.D.A. as -- for lack of a better term -- a forensic botanist is nearly entirely undocumented. One interesting exception is a case involving a suit lodged by Hillborn Darlington against the local gas company, in which the florist sought to demonstrate damage to his roses caused by a leaky gas main. True was called upon as an expert witness.
The earlier portions of True's career are partially documented in a series of notebooks maintained while he was a student at the University of Leipzig in 1893-1894, by a miscellaneous assortment of notes, and by a very small number of letters with family members in Series II.
The True Papers may be most valuable as a resource for examining True's activities on behalf of several professional organizations and institutions, including the Philadelphia Society for Promoting Agriculture, the Morris Arboretum, the Pennsylvania Horticulture Society, and the Allegheny Forest Experiment Station. Although most of the correspondence relating to these organizations is of an administrative nature, they are useful for understanding the role those organizations fulfilled in mediating between academia and the great public. As a member of Committee of One Hundred on Scientific Research of the American Association for the Advancement of Science, True was also involved in evaluating support for basic research in academia and the (inadequate) range of salaries.
Series I. Professional correspondence 1899-1939 2.5 linear feet
Series II. Personal correspondence 1862-1938 2 linear feet
Series III. Notebooks 1889-1929 0.5 linear feet
Series IV. Diaries 1883-1926 0.5 linear feet
Series V. Printed material 1846-1938 0.5 linear feet
Biographical/Historical note
The botanist Rodney Howard True (1866-1940) was born and raised in southern Wisconsin, the son of the transplanted New Englanders, John M. and Mary Annie (Beede) True. A farmer, occasional schoolmaster, and state legislator, John True instilled in each of his five children a strong interest in education, and provided them with the academic skills to match. Each of True children graduated from the University of Wisconsin -- Rodney in 1890, followed by Gordon (1894), Ernest (1896), Eunice M. (1905), and Katherine (1910) -- and four of them went on to careers in academia. In addition to Rodney, Gordon worked in animal husbandry at the University of California, while Katherine and Eunice taught at Berea College in Kentucky.
Rodney True's interest in botany was sparked during his high school years, and blossomed at university. After receiving his BS, he was encouraged to continue his studies through a University Fellowship, receiving his MS in 1892. After working as principal of the Wisconsin Academy for a year to shore up his finances, he went overseas to complete his training, studying botany and zoology at the University of Leipzig under Wilhelm Pfeffer, and receiving his doctorate in 1895.
For several years after his return to the states, True passed through academic vagabondage, teaching phamacognosy at the University of Wisconsin for three years, and serving as an assistant at Radcliffe (1899-1900) and as lecturer in botany at Harvard (1899-1901). From Harvard, however, he secured an important position overseeing the physiological research in the Bureau of Plant Industry of the U.S. Department of Agriculture. During his years at the U.S.D.A., True's own research shifted away from the general botany that had previously occupied him to concentrate on ionic exchange and the absorption of calcium and other mineral nutrients by plants, but he also gained a measure of fame as a "trouble shooter" for the public. Sometimes known as the Sherlock Holmes of plant detectives, he was charged with identifying and combating destructive or invasive plants. His most famous "cases" were the discovery of the source of a mold infecting the cigar industry and the identification of jimson weed as the culprit in "locoing" livestock in the western states, both of which had a profound economic impact.
In 1920, True left the U.S.D.A. under unusual, and less than favorable circumstances. Facing a reduced appropriation for his unit, he resisted the temptation to eliminate staff or lower salaries by reducing his budget through his own resignation. Although he left without having another position in hand, he was soon landed as professor of botany at the University of Pennsylvania, where he spent the remainder of his career. Despite a heavy load teaching everything from elementary botany to advanced plant physiology, he remained active in professional organizations and continued to publish in plant physiology, pathology, and economic botany. After Lydia Morris donated the land and endowment to establish the University's Morris Arboretum in 1932, True became the Arboretum's first Director, serving from 1933 until 1939. He was granted emeritus status at the University in 1937.
Beginning with his article, "Thomas Jefferson in Relation to Botany" in 1916, True devoted increasing time to the history of the plant sciences. Particularly after his remove to Philadelphia in 1920, he worked intensively on Jefferson and André Michaux, the botany of the Lewis and Clark Expedition, and more generally, on the history of agriculture. After his remove to Penn, the majority of his research was devoted to historical topics. True was a founding member of the Agricultural History Society in 1919, serving the first of his three terms as its first president, and he was active in the Pennsylvania Horticultural Society and the Philadelphia Society for Promoting Agriculture. He was elected to the American Philosophical Society in 1923. True also developed a deep interest in the status of his profession, becoming a member of the Committee of One Hundred on Scientific Research of the American Association for the Advancement of Science. During his time at Penn, he helped write several reports on support for basic research in universities and the financial position of university professors, making the case for higher wages.
True was married twice, to Katherine McAssey (d. 1926) and Martha. A son by his first marriage, Rodney Philip (Philip), became a noted plant pathologist in his own right. After several years of illness and physical decline, Rodney True died in his home at the Arboretum on April 8, 1940.
Allegheny Forest Experiment Station; American Association for the Advancement of Science. Committee of One Hundred on Scientific Research; Arndt, C. H.; Bartram, John, 1699-1777; Frazer, John; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826; Michaux, André, 1746-1802; Okie, John M.; Pennsylvania Horticultural Society; Philadelphia Society for Promoting Agriculture.; True, Katherine McAssey, d.1926; University of Pennsylvania. Morris Arboretum; Universität Leipzig; Agriculture--History; Blueprints; Botanical gardens--Pennsylvania; Botany; Botany--History; California--Description and travel; Diaries.; Field notes.; Franklinia alatamaha; Haiti--Description and travel; Maps; Notebooks; Photographs; Plant physiology
- Series I. Professional correspondence, 1899-1939; 2.5 Linear feet
  Scope and Contents note
  Rodney True's professional correspondence is heavily stilted toward the years spent at the University of Pennsylvania, post-1920. Although there is comparatively little to document True's work as a plant physiologist, the letters offer insight into his historical research, particularly on Thomas Jefferson and the Bartrams, and his activities on behalf of the Philadelphia Society for Promoting Agriculture (P.S.P.A.) and the Pennsylvania Horticultural Society. In addition to the folders filed under the name of the organization, several individual correspondents were involved with the P.S.P.A., most notably George F. Curwen and John M. Okie.
  There is some documentation of his activities as Director of the Morris Arboretum of the University of Pennsylvania and administrative correspondence relating to the Allegheny Forest Experiment Station run by the U.S.D.A.
  True's correspondence with John Frazer represents the happy merger of his interests in botany and history. True and Frazer exchanged a number of letters in their efforts to determine the original site of discovery of the "Franklin Tree," Franklinia alatamaha (also called Gordonia alatamaha), but were also busy exchanging information of plant physiology. True's correspondence with I.I.R. Henry is focused on study of the Bartrams and Bartam's Garden.
  An interesting series of letters relate to the "Darlington Gas Case," the Darlington Florists sued the local gas company over damage to its plants from a leaky gas main. True's plant forensic skills were called in to testify in a case that eventually made its way to the Pennsylvania Supreme Court before being decided in favor of the plaintiffs. A series of newspaper clippings related to the case are housed in Series V.
  Other correspondence of note includes a series of letters from the botanist C.H. Arndt describing his work in Haiti in the 1920s, letters from George F. Mitchell on tea (True had an interest in promoting tea cultivation in America), and the letters of several correspondents relating to botany and natural history in Maine, where True summered (see, e.g., Frank Morgan Jones, William T. Hussey, Mary Carpenter Kelley, Anne E. Perkins).
  - Academy of Natural Sciences (Box 1)
  - Ackley, Louise (Box 1)
  - Adams, Joseph (Box 1)
  - Addison, Steaven (Box 1)
  - Agricultural History Society, 4 folders (Box 1)
    Anderson, Russell H.
    Edwards, Everett E.
    Carrier, Lyman
    Stine, C. C.
    Wilson, M. L.
    Kellar, Herbert A.
  - Albertson, Alice C. (Box 1)
  - Albertson, F. W. (Box 1)
  - Albrecht, Otto E. (Box 1)
  - Allegheny Forest Experiment Station, 7 folders (Box 1)
    Cope, Francis R.
    Forbes, R. D.
    Schramm, J. R.
    Silcox, F. A.
    True, Rodney H.
    Lipman, Jacob G.
    Schnur, F. Luther
    Schuster, George L.
    Appleby, Paul H.
    Andrews, H. J.
    Chapline, W. R.
    Clapp, Earl H.
    Swartley, John C.
    Wood, O. M.
    Foley, John
    McClung, C. E.
    Smith, J. Spencer
    Wallace, H. A.
    Whitman, Ezra B.
    Doak, K. D.
    Kriebley Ralph M.
    Perry, George S.
    Wildman, Edward E.
  - Allen, C. E. (Box 1)
  - Allen, William B. (Box 1)
  - Allen, E. W. (Box 1)
  - Allen, Henry Butler (Box 1)
  - Allyn, Herman B. (Box 1)
  - Alsberg, Carl L. (Box 1)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science (Box 1)
    Livingston, Burton E.
    Baker, O. E.
    Bastin, Edson S.
    Daly, Reginald
    Kay, G.
    Littlefield, May
    Hughes, A. L.
    Metcalf, Maynard M.
    Randall, H. M.
    Raney, M. L.
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science. Committee of One Hundred of Scientific Research, 6 folders (Box 2)
    Bowie, William
    Noyes, W. A.
    Hargitt, George T.
    Taylor, Walter P.
    White, David.
  - American Association of University Professors (Box 1)
    Himstead, Ralph E.
  - American Birth Control League (Box 1)
  - American Foundation for the Blind (Box 1)
  - American Historical Association (Box 1)
  - American Library Association (Box 1)
  - American Library Service (Box 1)
  - American Philosophical Society, 5 folders (Box 1)
    Conklin, E. G.
    Hanson, Laura E.
    Moore, Percy
    Morris, Roland S.
    Noonan, Julia
    Sioussat, St.-G. L.
    Skinker, C. F.
  - American Society of Agronomy (Box 1)
  - American Society of Plant Physiologists (Box 1)
  - Anam, Arthur W. (Box 1)
  - Anthony, Pierce W. (Box 1)
  - Anti-Blue Law Association of Pennsylvania (Box 1)
  - Arndt, C. H. (Box 1)
  - "Associate Administrators--Duties and Qualifications" (Box 1)
  - Atkins, Charles D. (Box 1)
  - Atlantic Refining Company - (Box 1)
  - Authentic Building and Loan Association (Box 1)
  - Automobile Club of Philadelphia (Box 1)
  - Balch, Francis N. (Box 1)
  - Baltimore and Ohio Railroad Company (Box 1)
  - Barber, Edson B. (Box 1)
  - Barnett, Claribel R. (Box 1)
  - Bartlett, J. E. (Box 1)
    John Wiley and Sons
  - Beal, Ruth (Box 1)
  - Bessey, Ernst A. (Box 1)
  - Bedlinger, Fred (Box 1)
  - Bergen, Fanny (Mrs. J. Y.) (Box 1)
  - Berne, Thelma G. (Box 1)
  - Bernhardt, F. (Box 1)
    A. Nash Company
  - Bibliography (Box 1)
  - Bidwell, Percy W. (Box 1)
  - Bills (Box 1)
  - Blackburn, Harry, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Blakeslee, A. F. (Box 1)
  - Blueprint, Gas Main and Darlington Greenhousesm Doylestown (Box 1)
  - Bogle, Sarah C. N. (Box 1)
  - Book of the Month Club (Box 1)
  - Booth, Nora (Box 1)
  - Borghesani, G. A. R. (Box 1)
  - Boston (Map) (Box 1)
  - Botanical Review (Box 1)
  - Botany photographs, Doylestown (Box 1)
  - Bowie, Booth (Box 1)
  - Boyd, Allen (Box 1)
  - Brakeley, George A. (Box 1)
  - Brand, Charles J., 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Brocq-Rousseau, D. (Box 1)
  - Broders S. B. (Box 1)
  - Brubaker, Albert P. (Box 1)
  - Buder, Samuel B. (Box 2)
  - Burke, R. B. (Box 2)
  - Burnham, E. Lewis (Box 2)
  - Burnshaw Automobile Corporation (Box 2)
  - Burkholder, Paul R. (Box 2)
  - Butler, June Rainsford (Box 2)
  - Cain, Stanley A. (Box 2)
  - Calcott, W. A. (Box 2)
  - Caldwell, Arthur C. (Box 2)
  - Calov, Curt (Box 2)
  - Calvert, Philip P. (Box 2)
  - Cardot, J. (Box 2)
  - Carrier, Lyman (Box 2)
  - Cattell, Jacques (Box 2)
  - Cennis, Will B. (Box 2)
  - Chadburn, John L. (Box 2)
  - Chambers, Franklin S. (Box 2)
  - Chapin, Mrs. Charles H. (Box 2)
  - Chase, Agnes (Box 2)
  - Chase, George (Box 2)
  - Cheney, Lellen S. (Box 2)
  - Chrysostem, Sister M., "Photosynthesis" (Box 2)
  - Clark, Ida M. (Box 2)
  - Claypool, John H. (Box 2)
    Re: Darlington gas case
  - Coale, J. S. (Box 2)
  - Coleman, R. V. (Box 2)
  - Collins, Lester (Box 2)
  - Colton, Harold S. (Box 2)
  - Communication to Internal Revenue Service (Box 2)
  - Conklin, E. G. (Box 2)
  - Connecticut Fire Insurance Company (Box 2)
  - Cope, Theodora (Box 2)
  - Cosmos Club, Washington, D. C. (Box 2)
  - Coulter, John.M. (Box 2)
  - Crane, H. L. (Box 2)
  - Craven, Avery O. (Box 2)
  - Crawford, H. Jean (Box 2)
  - Crawford, Joseph (Box 2)
  - Crocker, P. S. (Box 2)
  - Crocker, William (Box 2)
  - Cross, Whitman (Box 2)
  - Curwen, George F. (Box 2)
  - Dane County, Wisconsin (Map) (Box 2)
  - Darlington, E. D. (Box 2)
  - Darlington, Grace B. (Box 2)
  - Darlington, Hillborn (Box 2)
    Claypool, John H.
  - Darrow, George M. (Box 2)
  - Daugh, Robert B. (Box 2)
  - Davis, Bradley M. (Box 2)
  - Davis, H. Allen, Jr. (Box 2)
  - Davis, J. B. (Box 2)
  - Davis, Lucy Tennant (Box 2)
  - Davis, R. H. (Box 2)
  - Denny, Frank E. (Box 2)
  - Day, Margaret (Mrs. Charles) (Box 2)
  - DeForest, Howard (Box 2)
  - Dengler, Robert E. (Box 2)
  - Dewey, John (Box 2)
  - Dick, G. A. (Box 2)
  - Dictionary of American Biography (Box 2)
  - Dietrich, Irwin (Box 2)
  - Dolbey, Edward P., & Company (Box 2)
  - Donaldson, Henry K., & Company (Box 2)
  - Donovan, J. B., & Company (Box 2)
  - Drake, W. Eric (Box 2)
  - Duckett, Francis Howard (Box 2)
  - DuPont, Pierre (Box 2)
  - Engineering Council (Box 2)
  - Fair, John J. (Box 2)
  - Farley, Mrs. S. S. (Box 2)
  - Farlow, W. G. (Box 2)
  - Farr, Edward L. (Box 2)
  - Fernald, M. L. (Box 2)
  - Fernald, R. H. (Box 2)
  - Fiedler, Henry George (Box 2)
  - Fisher, Irving (Box 2)
  - Flint, Lewis H., "A Call for a New Deal in Chemistry" (Box 2)
  - Fisher, Mark Elwin (Box 2)
  - Flynn, John E. (Box 2)
  - Fogg, John M., Jr. (Box 2)
  - Follansbee, Mitchell (Box 2)
  - Food Shortage (Box 2)
  - Fox, Clarence E. (Box 2)
  - Franklin Institute of Philadelphia (Box 2)
  - Frazer, John, 4 folders (Box 2)
    Higgins, C. A.
    Hume, Harold
    Kloss, A. S.
    Mathis, W. B.
    Shull, C. A.
  - Fritsche, Carl B., "Forging an Alliance Between Industry and Agriculture" (Box 2)
  - Galloway, B. T. (Box 2)
    Doolittle, R. G.
    Fine, R. H.
    Osborn, R. D
    Wiley, H. W.
  - Gardner, V. R. (Box 2)
  - Gee, N. Gist (Box 2)
  - Geological Survey (Box 2)
  - Gies, William J. (Box 2)
  - Giles, Irvin K. (Box 2)
  - Gimbel, Ellis A. (Box 2)
  - Glück, H. (Box 2)
  - Goodell, A. E. (Box 2)
  - Greidenboel, Royden W. (Box 2)
  - Grimes, Eileen W. (Box 2)
  - Grout, A. J. (Box 2)
  - Gruberg Frederick C. (Box 2)
  - Guffey, Joseph J. (Box 2)
  - Haldeman, John W. (Box 2)
  - Hall, Edwin S. (Box 2)
  - Hammett, Frederick S. (Box 2)
  - Hanson, Laura E. (Box 2)
  - Harlow, N. E. (Box 2)
  - Harper, Francis (Box 2)
  - Harris & Ewing, Photographers (Box 2)
  - Harshberger, John W. (Box 2)
  - Hart, H. L. (Box 2)
  - Harvey, James A. (Box 2)
  - Harvey, R. B. (Box 2)
  - Hatton, R. Marion (Box 2)
  - Hawks, Emma B. (Box 2)
  - Hayes, Carlton J. H. (Box 2)
  - Heller, Jane R. (Box 2)
    Morris Arboretum
  - Henry, I. I. R. (Mrs. Bayard) (Box 2)
  - Henry, Mary G. (Mrs. J. Norman) (Box 2)
  - Hergesheimer and Finkbiner (Box 2)
  - Hermann, D. May (Box 2)
  - Hibbard, C. V. (Box 2)
  - Hicks, Elva E. (Box 2)
  - Himstead, Ralph E. (Box 2)
  - Hock, Charles W. (Box 2)
  - Hogg, George Jardain (Box 2)
  - Holroyd, Roland (Box 3)
  - Honey, E. E. (Box 3)
  - Hoopes, Edward (Box 3)
  - Horvath, A. A. (Box 3)
  - Houston Hall Book Department (Box 3)
  - Hunter, Hannah (Box 3)
  - Hussey, William T. (Box 3)
  - Hutcheson, Martha B. (Mrs. William A.) (Box 3)
  - Itineraries (Box 3)
  - Jackson, L. W. R. (Box 3)
  - Jarvis, Richard A. (Box 3)
  - Jayne, Horace H. F. (Box 3)
  - Jenks, John S. (Box 3)
  - Johnson, Allen (Box 3)
  - Johnson, Emory R. (Box 3)
  - Johnson, Fred (Box 3)
  - Johnson, John C. (Box 3)
  - Johnston, Robert W. (Box 3)
  - Johnson, T. C. (Box 3)
  - Jones, Frank Morgan (Box 3)
  - Jones, L. R. (Box 3)
  - Jones, Orann M. (Box 3)
  - Journal, October, 1918 (Box 3)
  - Kays, S. A. (Box 3)
  - Keller, Herbert A. (Box 3)
  - Kelley, Mary Carpenter (Box 3)
  - Kelsey, R. W. (Box 3)
  - Kern, Frank D. (Box 3)
  - King, William Bruce (Box 3)
  - King-Scheerer Corporation (Box 3)
  - Kirk, Sophia (Box 3)
  - Klein, Louis (Box 3)
  - Klingelsmith, Margaret Center (Box 3)
  - Koehlers, K. F., Antiquarium (Box 3)
  - Lewis, Mrs. O. G. L. (Box 3)
  - Library of Congress, Manuscript Division (Box 3)
  - Linden, J. W. (Box 3)
  - Lippincott Company (Box 3)
  - Lippincott, J. Bertram (Box 3)
  - Livingston, Burton.E. (Box 3)
  - Loehn, Rodney C. (Box 3)
  - Loewing, Walter F. (Box 3)
  - Log of Collecting Trip, 1931 (Box 3)
  - Logs of Collecting Trips, 1936 (Box 3)
  - Log of Trip to Mesa, California, Albuquerque, etc., 1930 (Box 3)
  - Longenecker, G. William (Box 3)
  - Lowe, Mrs. Josephine D. (Box 3)
  - Loyalty Pledge (Box 3)
  - Lutz, William (Box 3)
  - McCormack, F. Wells (Box 3)
  - MacDonald, H. H. (Box 3)
  - MacDougal, D. (Box 3)
  - McFarland, J. Horace (Box 3)
  - MacFarlane, John Muirhead (Box 3)
  - McHenry, A. Scott (Box 3)
  - MacLean, H. I. (Box 3)
  - Macy, R. H., & Co. (Box 3)
  - Maitland, Virginia K. (Box 3)
  - Mann, Alan N. (Box 3)
  - Map Store (Box 3)
  - Marsh, C. D. (Box 3)
  - Mehorter, Rose (Box 3)
  - Melchers, L. E. (Box 3)
  - Mendenhall, John C. (Box 3)
  - Merrill, M. C. (Box 3)
  - Mills, W. H. (Box 3)
  - Milstead, Edwin H. (Box 3)
  - Minnick, J. H. (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous notes (Box 3)
  - Mitchell, George F. (Box 3)
  - Mooers, C. A. (Box 3)
  - Moon, George (Box 3)
  - Morey, H. F. (Box 3)
  - Morgan, Joy E. (Box 3)
  - Morison, A. J. (Box 3)
  - Morris Arboretum, Board of Managers (Box 3)
  - Morris, Lawrence J. (Box 3)
  - Moulton, F. R. (Box 3)
  - Mullekin, Lee (Box 3)
  - Mulroy, J. R. (Box 3)
  - Mumford, E. M. (Box 3)
  - Musser, Paul H. (Box 3)
  - National Historical Park, Morristown, New Jersey (Box 3)
  - Neal, Oliver H. (Box 3)
  - Neal, Oliver M., Jr. (Box 3)
  - Neale, Walter (Box 3)
  - Nelson, Martin (Box 3)
  - Newbold, Arthur E., Jr. (Box 3)
  - Norton, Arthur H. (Box 3)
  - Notes, Records of Analyses and Experiments, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Ogilvie, William V. (Box 3)
  - Okie, John M., 6 folders (Box 3)
    Pennsylvania Society for Promoting Agriculture
  - Olive, Edgar W. (Box 3)
  - Olson, Nils A. (Box 3)
  - O'Neil, James (Box 3)
  - Owen, D. E. (Box 3)
  - Palmer, S. C. (Box 3)
  - Parsons, Charles L. (Box 3)
  - Pennell, Francis W. (Box 3)
  - Penniman, Josiah H. (Box 3)
  - Pennock, Edward (Box 3)
  - Pennsylvania Horticultural Society, 9 folders (Box 4)
    Foley, Daniel J.
    McFarland, M. C.
    Root, Fannie A.
    Samuel, Maria B.
    Stout, C. Frederick C.
    True, Rodney H., "The Relation of Plants to Each Other"
    Wister, John C.
  - Pepper, George W. (Box 3)
  - Perkins, Anne E. (Box 4)
  - Pershing, John J. (Box 4)
  - Pettitt, L. A., Jr. (Box 4)
    Dupree, Richard
  - Phelps, Isaac King (Box 4)
  - Phi Beta Kappa (Box 4)
  - Philadelphia Botanical Club (Box 4)
  - Philadelphia Chamber Music Association (Box 4)
  - Philadelphia Society for Promoting Agriculture, 6 folders (Box 4)
    Curwen, George F.
    Hoopes, Edward
    Iben, Icko
    Jerabek, Esther
    Okie, John M.
    Pickett, Ralph
    Stern, Edward, & Company
    True, Rodney H., "A Sketch of the History of the Society"
    Wister, Frances
    Woodward, Carl R.
  - Piggott, C. B. (Box 4)
  - Plymale, Lewis (Box 4)
  - Potter, F. D. (Box 4)
  - Prussing, E. E. (Box 4)
  - Pugh, Marshall (Box 4)
  - Quinn, R. J. (Box 4)